黄刚是二零二零年初中毕业生，学业水平和
高中阶段学校招生考试
英语试题。
第一节，听句子。
从每小题所给的
A B goes to school by bus every day.
三个选项中，选出与所听句子内容相符的图片。
听完每个句子后，你将有五秒钟的作答时间。
每个句子读两遍。
I usually play soccer with my friends in my free time.
3. Children like to make snowman on snowy days.
Children like to make snowman on snowy days.
4. Chinese people enjoy mooncakes on the mid -autumn festival.
Chinese people enjoy mooncakes on the mid -autumn festival.
五，
Last weekend, we volunteered to clean up the city park.
Last weekend, we volunteered
第二节。
听下面六段对话，每段对话后面有几个小题，从题后所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你将有十或十五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话读两遍。
听第六段对话，回答第六七小题。
we volunteered went to Beijing with my family.
Really? Did you do anything special?
Well, we visited the Great Wall.
It was so exciting.
How was the food there?
It was delicious.
I love Beijing duck best.
Hi Maria. How was your vacation?
Great. I went to Beijing with my family.
Really? Did you do anything special?
Well, we visited the Great Wall.
It was so exciting.
How was the food there?
It was delicious.
I love Beijing duck best.
听。
第七段对话，回答第八九小题。
Mike, you don't look well.
What's the matter?
I have a headache.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Did you see a doctor?
Yes. My parents took me to the hospital this morning.
What did the doctor say?
The doctor said it was nothing serious.
Maybe you should have a rest.
Mike, you don't look well.
What's the matter?
I have a headache.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Did you see a doctor?
Yes. My parents took me to the hospital this morning.
What did the doctor say?
The doctor said it was nothing serious.
Maybe you should have a rest.
听第八段对话，回答第十、十一小题。
What are you reading, Lucy?
The Old Man and the Sea by Hemingway.
Now, I know why you are so good at writing stories.
Yes, I want to be a writer.
Really? How are you going to become a writer?
Well, I'm going to keep on writing stories, of course.
What do you want to be, Alan?
I want to be a doctor like Zhong Nanshan.
He is a hero in my heart.
Great! Try your best and you can be anything you want.
What are you reading, Lucy?
The Old Man and the Sea by Hemingway.
Now, I know why you are so good at writing stories.
Yes, I want to be a writer.
Really? How are you going to become a writer?
Well, I'm going to keep on writing stories, of course.
What do you want to be, Alan?
I want to be a doctor like Zhong Nanshan.
He is a hero in my heart.
Great! Try your best and you can be anything you want.
听第九段对话，回答第十二、十三、十四小题。
Excuse me, could you please tell me where I can buy a dictionary?
Yes, there's a bookstore on Center Street.
Oh, could you tell me how to get to Center Street?
Sure, it's not far from here.
Just walk past the bank and then turn right.
The bookstore is on the right, next to the post office.
Oh, how long will it take me to get there?
About ten minutes.
I'll walk there.
Thanks a lot.
Excuse me, could you please tell me where I can buy a dictionary?
Yes, there's a bookstore on Center Street.
Oh, could you tell me how to get to Center Street?
Sure, it's not far from here.
Just walk past the bank and then turn right.
The bookstore is on the right, next to the post office.
Oh, how long will it take me to get there?
About ten minutes.
I'll walk there.
Thanks a Hello, house of dumplings.
听第十段对话，回答第十五、十六、十七小题
Hello, I want to order some food, please.
Sure, what would you like?
I'd like beef and cabbage dumplings.
What size would you like?
A large bowl, please.
Okay, what else?
Um, I'd like some soup, too.
Okay, what kind soup would you like?
Tomato soup only.
Alright, what's your address, please?
18 Zhongshan Road, and my telephone number is 860 -7315.
Okay, thank you.
That'll be 68 yuan.
Hello, house of dumplings.
Hello, I want to order some food, please.
Sure, what would you like?
I'd like beef and cabbage dumplings.
What size would you like?
A large bowl, please.
Okay, what else?
Um, I'd like some soup, too.
Okay, what kind soup would you like?
Tomato soup only.
Alright, what's your address, please?
18 Zhongshan Road, and my telephone number is 860 -7315.
Okay, thank you.
That'll be 68 yuan.
听第十一段对话，回答第十八、十九、二十小题。
So Peter, here we are at the end of junior high.
Do you have any special memories?
Oh yeah, lots.
I remember losing my school bag in grade 7.
I remember that.
Some friends helped you look for it, remember?
Yes, and you found it.
Thanks for saving my life that day.
No problem. What about you, Lisa?
What do you remember?
I used to be scared of my English teacher, Mr.
Wang, in grade 8.
He was so strict.
I always did my homework carefully after class.
Yes, but that made you learn English well.
You are right.
I will always remember Mr.
Oh, this weekend, we are going to have a party to celebrate the end of junior high
school. Let's ask Mr.
Wang to join us.
Okay, let's go.
So Peter, here we are at the end of junior high.
Do you have any special memories?
Oh yeah, lots.
I remember losing my school bag in grade 7.
I remember that.
Some friends helped you look for it, remember?
Yes, and you found it.
Thanks for saving my life that day.
No problem. What about you, Lisa?
What do you remember?
I used to be scared of my English teacher, Mr.
in grade 8.
He was so strict.
I always did my homework carefully after class.
Yes, but that made you learn English well.
You are right.
I will always remember Mr.
Oh, this weekend, we are going to have a party to celebrate the end of junior high
school. Let's ask Mr.
Wang to join us.
Okay, let's go.
第三。
节。
听下面一篇短文。
根据你所听到的短文内容，选择能回答所提问题的最佳答案。
听完短文后，你将有二十五秒钟的作答时间。
短文读两遍。
us. Okay, let's us.
us. go. Let's ask join us.
Okay, let's go.
This is a story about a famous writer, Helen Keller.
When she was only 19 months old, she was ill.
Because of the illness,
she could not see or hear anything.
When she was 6, a young teacher,
came to her family and taught her how to read and write.
Later, when she was 10,
took her to visit another teacher.
That teacher taught her to speak.
Helen put her fingers on her teacher's face or into her mouth.
In this way, she learned how to speak.
After that, she went to university.
She began writing books and helping many blind people.
So she became popular and famous.
The world remembers her today as a brave and wonderful woman.
Though she was blind and deaf, she found a way to see and hear, and it helped many
people in the world.
This is a story about a famous writer, Helen Keller.
When she was only 19 months old, she was ill.
Because of the illness,
she could not see or hear anything.
When she was 6, a young teacher,
came to her family and taught her how to read and write.
Later, when she was 10, Annie took her to visit another teacher.
That teacher taught her to speak.
Helen put her fingers on her teacher's face or into her mouth.
In this way, she learned how to speak.
After that, she went to university.
She began writing books and helping many blind people.
So she became popular and famous.
The world remembers her today as a brave and wonderful woman.
Though she was blind and deaf, she found a way to see and hear, and it helped many
people in the world.
a famous Because of deaf, she to is
听力部分到此结束。